Guide to the George P. Hall & Son Photograph Collection [1876-1914] PR 24
© 2011 New-York Historical Society
- Series I: Photographs of Manhattan
  - Street Scenes - Mounted
    - Named Streets (includes parks and squares)
      - Fulton Street, looking west toward Hudson River, 1904 (Box 16, Folder 143)
      - Herald Square (3), 1904, 1909, undated (Box 16, Folder 144)
      - Hudson Park (2), 1903 (Box 16, Folder 144)
      - Liberty Street (2), [1908-1914] (Box 16, Folder 145)
      - Madison Avenue and 56th Street, undated (Box 16, Folder 146)
      - Madison Square Park, rooftop views (3), [1909-1914], undated (Box 16, Folder 146)
      - Madison Square Park and Dewey Arch from southwest, 1899 (Box 16, Folder 146)
      - Madison Square Park and Metropolitan Life Insurance Building, before and after tower construction (2), [1900], 1910 (Box 16, Folder 147)
      - Madison Square Park with Madison Square Tower, undated (Box 16, Folder 147)
      - Maiden Lane, at Gold and Liberty Streets, undated (Box 17, Folder 148)
      - Maiden Lane, campaign banner for Seth Low for Mayor, [1901-1903] (Box 17, Folder 148)
      - Maiden Lane, campaign banner for Taft and Sherman, 1908 (Box 17, Folder 148)
      - Nassau Street north from Wall Street, 1903 (Box 17, Folder 149)
      - Nassau Street, Fourth National Bank Building, 1913 (Box 17, Folder 149)
      - Nassau Street, north from Liberty Street, [1905] (Box 17, Folder 149)
      - Park Avenue at East 24th Street, [1900] (Box 17, Folder 150)
      - Park Row (10), [1902-1910], undated (Box 17, Folder 150-151)
      - Pine Street, between Broadway and Nassau Street, 1913 (Box 17, Folder 152)
      - Trinity Place, [1905] (Box 17, Folder 152)
      - Union Square, [1905], undated (Box 17, Folder 153)
      - Wall Street (7), [1905-1908], undated (Box 17, Folder 154-155)
      - West Street and Hudson River piers, [1900-1905] (Box 17, Folder 156)
    - Numbered Avenues
      - Fifth Avenue and 23rd Street, Hudson-Fulton Parade (2), 1909 (Box 18, Folder 157)
      - Fifth Avenue, 23rd through 30th Streets (2), 1903-[1905] (Box 18, Folder 157)
      - Fifth Avenue from 32nd through 56th Street (6), [1905]-1910, undated (Box 18, Folder 158)
      - Seventh Avenue, 392, including L. Estherson's Family Wine and Liquor Store, Pennsylvania Station demolition site in background, [1903] (Box 18, Folder 159)
    - Numbered Streets
      - 125th Street, view of viaduct, 1904 (Box 18, Folder 160)
  - Theaters - Unmounted
    - Academy of Music, undated (Box 18, Folder 161)
    - Alhambra Theatre, 126th Street and Seventh Avenue (2), undated (Box 18, Folder 161)
    - Belasco Theatre, 1903-1904 (Box 18, Folder 161)
    - Casino Theatre, undated (Box 18, Folder 161)
    - Eden Musee, 23rd Street, interior and exterior (2), undated (Box 18, Folder 161)
    - Grand Theatre, Grand Street, undated (Box 18, Folder 161)
    - Grand Opera House, undated (Box 18, Folder 161)
    - Hammerstein's Roof Garden and Victoria Theatre, [1908] (Box 18, Folder 162)
    - Harlem Opera House, 209 West 125th Street, undated (Box 18, Folder 162)
    - Hippodrome, Sixth Avenue at 43rd and 44th Streets (2), [1905] (Box 18, Folder 162)
    - Hudson Theatre, 1904 (Box 18, Folder 162)
    - Lyceum Theatre, 149 West 45th Street, [1904] (Box 18, Folder 162)
    - Madison Square Garden, original building [copy photograph, undated (Box 18, Folder 163)
    - Madison Square Garden, [1890, McKim, Mead & White], undated (Box 18, Folder 163)
    - Madison Square Garden, interiors, automobile show (3), [1904] (Box 18, Folder 163)
    - Majestic Theatre, [1904] (Box 18, Folder 163)
    - Manhattan Opera House, 1909 (Box 18, Folder 163)
    - Miner's Eighth Avenue Theatre, undated (Box 18, Folder 163)
    - New Amsterdam Theatre, exteriors and interiors (5), [1907], undated (Box 18, Folder 164)
    - New Theatre, Central Park West [demolished in 1931], 1909 (Box 18, Folder 164)
    - Payton's, interior [Sunshine Society], undated (Box 18, Folder 164)
    - Penn Theatre [small converted church], undated (Box 18, Folder 164)
    - Terrace Garden and Lexington Opera House, undated (Box 18, Folder 164)
  - Theaters - Mounted
    - Madison Square Garden, exteriors and interior view of Shoe Manufacturers' Convention, [1895], undated (Box 18, Folder 165)
    - Muschenheim's Arena, undated (Box 18, Folder 166)
    - Proctor's Pleasure Palace, [1900-1914] (Box 18, Folder 166)
- Series II: Photographs of The Bronx, Brooklyn, Queens and Staten Island
  Series II consists of approximately 300 photographs of outer boroughs of New York City. Photographs are arranged alphabetically by borough and thereunder alphabetically by title/description. Because the subseries for Brooklyn is much larger than for the other boroughs, it has been further subdivided as described below. Each subseries or Brooklyn subject division is divided into unmounted and mounted photographs to accommodate conservation housing needs. Numbers in parentheses refer to the number of photographs available for that subject.
  Photographs of The Bronx, Queens and Staten Island are very few. Railroad and streets scenes are complemented by a few photographs of residences, schools, and institutions, such as New York University's Library and the Hall of Fame in The Bronx. A view of Queens from the Queensboro bridge toll plaza, and a photograph of a toll gate building at Jamaica Avenue and Van Wyck Boulevard are available in the Queens subseries. The few photographs of Staten Island sites include those of the Anson Phelps Stokes House and the Staten Island Ferry Terminal in St. George.
  Photographs of Hall's own borough of Brooklyn are more numerous and have been arranged in the following categories: Buildings, Churches, Cityscapes and Panoramic Views, Parks and Resorts, Residences, Statues and Monuments, and Street Scenes. Thereunder they are arranged alphabetically by title/description.
  Buildings depicted include many prominent Brooklyn Institutions, including the Brooklyn Academy of Music, City Hall, the Brooklyn Institute of Arts and Sciences (Brooklyn Museum), and historic Ebbets Field. Images abound of Lutheran, Roman Catholic, Presbyterian and Dutch Reformed churches. Cityscapes and Panoramic Views includes several rooftops views of Brooklyn, many of which include the riverfront.
  The Parks and Resorts category is large, and contains views of Coney Island beaches, resorts, and hotels, as well as views of Prospect Park and Fort Greene Park. The new popular developments along Coney Islands beaches in the 1890s through the 1910s are particularly well documented. The Manhattan Beach Hotel and the Oriental Hotel are captured from a variety of vantage points, including those from ships off the coast.
  Included in the Residences category is 642 Flatbush Avenue, the home of George P. Hall in the 1890s. Statues and Monuments includes a few views of the U.S. Grant Statue at Bedford and Dean Streets. Street Scenes are primarily along Atlantic Avenue, and include one unidentified parade scene.
  - The Bronx - Unmounted
    - Barn, 18th century, undated (Box 19, Folder 167)
    - Bedford Reform Church, later Aurora Grata, Bedford Avenue, undated (Box 19, Folder 167)
    - Bedford Park Racetrack, undated (Box 19, Folder 167)
    - Elevated railroad (2), undated (Box 19, Folder 167)
    - Evergreen Avenue, unidentified Dutch frame house, undated (Box 19, Folder 167)
    - Feulner's Hotel, [1902] (Box 19, Folder 167)
    - Gothic church and rectory, undated (Box 19, Folder 167)
    - Lincoln Hospital, undated (Box 19, Folder 167)
    - Morris High School, East 166th Street (2), undated (Box 19, Folder 167)
    - Victorian cottage, undated (Box 19, Folder 167)
  - The Bronx - Mounted
    - Jamaica Avenue, undated (Box 19, Folder 168)
    - New York University (Uptown) Library and Hall of Fame (2), [1905], undated (Box 19, Folder 168)
  - Brooklyn
    - Buildings -- Unmounted
      - Armories (6), undated (Box 19, Folder 169)
      - Brooklyn Academy of Music (2), 1909, [1909] (Box 19, Folder 170)
      - Brooklyn City Railroad Co., Clinton and Remsen Streets, undated (Box 19, Folder 170)
      - Brooklyn Hospital, undated (Box 19, Folder 170)
      - Brooklyn Institute of Arts & Sciences [Brooklyn Museum], 1909 (Box 19, Folder 170)
      - Brooklyn Savings Bank, Pierrepont and Clinton Streets, [1910] (Box 19, Folder 170)
      - Brooklyn Warehouse and Storage Co., undated (Box 19, Folder 170)
      - Burgess, Randolph, Real Estate, 583 Flatbush Avenue, undated (Box 19, Folder 170)
      - City Hall, undated (Box 19, Folder 170)
      - Collegiate and Polytechnic Institute, undated (Box 19, Folder 170)
      - Crescent Club, 1909 (Box 19, Folder 170)
      - Dime Savings Bank of Brooklyn, 1909 (Box 19, Folder 170)
      - Fire Headquarters, undated (Box 19, Folder 171)
      - Garfield Building, undated (Box 19, Folder 171)
      - Germania Club, undated (Box 19, Folder 171)
      - Green-Wood Cemetery Gatehouse, undated (Box 19, Folder 171)
      - Hall of Records, undated (Box 19, Folder 171)
      - Havemeyer & Elder's Sugar Refinery, [1895-1910] (Box 19, Folder 171)
      - Heights Casino, 75 Montague Street, undated (Box 19, Folder 171)
      - Hotel Bossert, undated (Box 19, Folder 171)
      - Hotel Montague, undated (Box 19, Folder 171)
      - Kings County Wheelmen's Clubhouse, undated (Box 19, Folder 171)
      - Kings County Penitentiary, undated (Box 19, Folder 171)
      - Lawyers Title Insurance and Trust Company, undated (Box 19, Folder 171)
      - Lockwood Academy, undated (Box 19, Folder 171)
      - Long Island Business College, undated (Box 19, Folder 171)
      - Majestic Theatre, [1905] (Box 19, Folder 172)
      - Masonic Temple, Clermont and Lafayette Avenues, 1909 (Box 19, Folder 172)
      - Mechanics Bank, Court Street, undated (Box 19, Folder 172)
      - Midwood Club, undated (Box 19, Folder 172)
      - Mills, James Carpenter Shop, [1895-1910] (Box 19, Folder 172)
      - Montauk Club, undated (Box 19, Folder 172)
      - Mount Prospect Water Tower, undated (Box 19, Folder 172)
      - Park Department Building, 1909 (Box 19, Folder 172)
      - People's Bank, undated (Box 19, Folder 172)
      - Pratt Institute, undated (Box 19, Folder 172)
      - Public School 108, undated (Box 19, Folder 172)
      - Raymond Street Jail, undated (Box 19, Folder 173)
      - St. Mary's Hospital, undated (Box 19, Folder 173)
      - St. Phebe's Hospital, undated (Box 19, Folder 173)
      - Seney Hospital, [1895-1910] (Box 19, Folder 173)
      - Telephone Building, Smith Street, undated (Box 19, Folder 173)
      - Temple Bar Building (2), undated (Box 19, Folder 173)
      - Thomas Jefferson Building, undated (Box 19, Folder 173)
      - Touraine Hotel, undated (Box 19, Folder 173)
      - Union League Club, undated (Box 19, Folder 173)
      - U.S. Post Office, Brooklyn Heights, undated (Box 19, Folder 173)
      - Williamsburgh Savings Bank, undated (Box 19, Folder 173)
      - Y.M.C.A., Bedford and Monroe Streets, undated (Box 19, Folder 173)
      - Y.M.C.A. Naval Branch, Sands Street, undated (Box 19, Folder 173)
    - Buildings -- Mounted
      - Brooklyn Institute of Arts & Sciences (Brooklyn Museum), 1910 (Box 19, Folder 174)
      - Brooklyn Warehouse and Storage Co., undated (Box 19, Folder 174)
      - Ebbets Field (2), undated (Box 19, Folder 174)
      - Unidentified toll gate building (2 copies), undated (Box 19, Folder 175)
    - Churches - Unmounted
      - Brooklyn Tabernacle [photo of architectural rendering by J.B. Snook & Son Architects, 1890], undated (Box 20, Folder 176)
      - Flatbush Reformed Church, undated (Box 20, Folder 176)
      - Flatbush Dutch Reformed Church Cemetery, undated (Box 20, Folder 176)
      - Flatlands Dutch Reformed Church, undated (Box 20, Folder 176)
      - Grace Reform Church, undated (Box 20, Folder 176)
      - Household of Faith [William N. Pile, pastor portrayed], [1895-1910] (Box 20, Folder 176)
      - Lutheran Church, 2782 Finmore Street(?), Parish house yard, undated (Box 20, Folder 176)
      - Pilgrim [Swedish] Congregational Church, [1895-1910] (Box 20, Folder 176)
      - Plymouth Church, undated (Box 20, Folder 176)
      - Queen of All Saints Roman Catholic Church, [1895-1910] (Box 20, Folder 176)
      - St. Patrick's Roman Catholic Church, undated (Box 20, Folder 176)
      - St. Paul's Roman Catholic Church, undated (Box 20, Folder 176)
      - Second United Presbyterian Church, Atlantic Avenue (2), [1895-1910] (Box 20, Folder 176)
      - Unidentified Church, undated (Box 20, Folder 176)
    - Cityscapes and Panoramic Views - Unmounted
      - Atlantic Avenue Docks, undated (Box 20, Folder 177)
      - Brooklyn Heights, bird's-eye view to northwest, undated (Box 20, Folder 177)
      - Brooklyn Museum area from east, undated (Box 20, Folder 177)
      - Downtown Brooklyn, rooftop view (2), undated (Box 20, Folder 177)
      - Elevated railroad views (2), undated (Box 20, Folder 177)
      - Flatbush Avenue Long Island Railroad Station, under construction, 1906 (Box 20, Folder 177)
      - Wall Street Ferry Terminal, [1910], undated (Box 20, Folder 177)
    - Cityscapes and Panoramic Views - Mounted
      - Brooklyn Bridge approach and view to south, undated (Box 20, Folder 178)
      - Brooklyn Navy Yards, [1910] (Box 20, Folder 178)
      - Flatbush Avenue and Eastern Parkway, undated (Box 20, Folder 178)
      - Morson's Docks, [1905] (Box 20, Folder 178)
      - Rooftop views to northeast from Brooklyn Hospital (2), [1904] (Box 20, Folder 178)
    - Parks and Resorts - Unmounted
      - Bergen Beach (3), undated (Box 20, Folder 179)
      - Coney Island/Brighton Beach, amusement parks (13), 1908-1911, undated (Box 20, Folder 180)
      - Coney Island/Brighton Beach, beaches and hotels (15), 1905-1911, undated (Box 20, Folder 181)
      - Fort Greene Park and Prison Ship Martyrs Monument (3), [1900], 1909 (Box 20, Folder 182)
      - Prospect Park, Grand Army Plaza and entrance (8), undated (Box 20, Folder 183)
      - Prospect Park, 1904-1913 (Box 20, Folder 184)
    - Parks and Resorts - Mounted
      - Coney Island, general views (8), [1896-1908], undated (Box 21, Folder 185-187)
      - Manhattan Beach, general views (10), [1905-1910], undated (Box 21, Folder 188-190)
      - Manhattan Beach, Long Island Railroad Depot (3), [1905-1910] (Box 21, Folder 191)
      - Manhattan Beach, Manhattan Beach Hotel (8), [1905-1910], undated (Box 21, Folder 192-193)
      - Manhattan Beach, Oriental Hotel (17), [1903-1905], undated (Box 22, Folder 194-197)
      - Prospect Park (4), undated (Box 22, Folder 198)
      - Sheepshead Bay (3), undated (Box 22, Folder 199)
      - Sheepshead Bay, D. Olagner's Ocean View Hotel (3), [1905], undated (Box 22, Folder 200)
    - Residences - Unmounted
      - Teunis Bergen House, northwest corner of Flatbush Avenue and Cortelyou Road, undated (Box 22, Folder 201)
      - Ditmas-Suydam House, 1160 Flatbush Avenue, [1890] (Box 22, Folder 201)
      - George P. Hall Residence, 642 Putnam Avenue (2), [1894-1900] (Box 22, Folder 201)
      - McElvery [Murphy] House, 624 Flatbush Avenue(2), undated (Box 22, Folder 201)
      - Captain John Schenck House, Avenue U and 63rd Street, undated (Box 22, Folder 201)
      - Remsen House, E. 48th Street, undated (Box 22, Folder 201)
      - Vanderbilt House, Flatbush, undated (Box 22, Folder 201)
      - Vernon House, Lafayette and Clinton Avenues, undated (Box 22, Folder 201)
      - Unidentified residences, includes barns (10), [1895-1910], undated (Box 22, Folder 202)
    - Statues and Monuments - Unmounted
      - Henry Ward Beecher statue at Court and Fulton Streets, undated (Box 22, Folder 203)
      - Ulysses S. Grant statue, Bedford Avenue at Dean Street (2), [1896-1914] (Box 22, Folder 203)
      - Henry Warner Slocum Monument, Eastern Parkway, 1906 (Box 22, Folder 203)
    - Street Scenes - Unmounted
      - Atlantic Avenue, tunnel, undated (Box 22, Folder 204)
      - Atlantic Avenue at Bedford Avenue, Long Island Railroad crossing, undated (Box 22, Folder 204)
      - Atlantic Avenue near East New York, undated (Box 22, Folder 204)
      - Atlantic Avenue and Fifth Avenue, railroad crossing, undated (Box 22, Folder 204)
      - Atlantic Avenue and Flatbush Avenue, 1903 (Box 22, Folder 204)
      - Atlantic Avenue at Georgia Avenue, 1891 (Box 22, Folder 204)
      - Atlantic Avenue and Nostrand Avenue, trolleys (2), [1895-1910] (Box 22, Folder 204)
      - Clinton and Greene Streets, undated (Box 22, Folder 204)
      - Court Street at Joralemon Street, [1895-1910] (Box 22, Folder 204)
      - Montague Street, Real Estate Exchange and Public Library, undated (Box 22, Folder 204)
      - Navy Street, undated (Box 22, Folder 205)
      - Remsen Street (2), [1895-1910] (Box 22, Folder 205)
      - Vanderbilt Avenue, school children, undated (Box 22, Folder 205)
      - Wallabout Market, [1895-1910] (Box 22, Folder 205)
      - Willoughby Street, undated (Box 22, Folder 205)
      - Unidentified parade scene, undated (Box 22, Folder 205)
  - Queens - Unmounted
    - College Point, Flushing Bay [photograph of bird's eye map], undated (Box 23, Folder 206)
    - Jamaica Avenue, old house near Long Island Railroad, undated (Box 23, Folder 206)
    - Toll gate building, Jamaica Avenue and Van Wyck Boulevard, [1897] (Box 23, Folder 206)
  - Queens - Mounted
    - Long Island City, undated (Box 23, Folder 207)
    - Queens view from Queensboro Bridge Plaza, undated (Box 23, Folder 206)
  - Staten Island - Unmounted
    - Brownings Prohibition Park, undated (Box 23, Folder 208)
    - Camp Kill Kane, exterior and view of road (2), undated (Box 23, Folder 208)
    - Staten Island Ferry Terminal, St. George, undated (Box 23, Folder 208)
    - Anson Phelps Stokes House (5), undated (Box 23, Folder 208)
- Series III: Photographs Outside New York
  Series III consists of photographs of sites in the United States, focusing especially on areas of Long Island, Connecticut, and New Jersey. A few photographs of St. Louis, Missouri are also available, and include a view of the construction of buildings for the 1904 Louisiana Purchase Exposition. A Newark, New Jersey photograph shows President Theodore Roosevelt standing with a statue of Abraham Lincoln by Gutzon Borglum in front of the Essex County Courthouse, probably taken during his dedication of the statue in 1911. A large group of mostly interiors of Sagtikos Manor, in West Bay Shore, Long Island are included in this series. This manor house was built in 1692 by New York mayor Stephanus Van Cortlandt, and was expanded twice in the eighteenth and nineteenth centuries. The manor's antique furnishings are depicted here, include a bed in which George Washington is believed to have slept during a trip through Long Island in 1790.
  - Unmounted
    - Connecticut
      - Hartford - Aetna Life Insurance Company, undated (Box 23, Folder 209)
      - New Haven - Vanderbilt Hall, Yale University, undated (Box 23, Folder 209)
    - District of Columbia
      - U.S. Capitol, undated (Box 23, Folder 209)
      - Library of Congress, undated (Box 23, Folder 209)
    - Florida
      - Palm Beach Hotel, veranda and golf driving range (3), undated (Box 23, Folder 209)
    - New Jersey
      - Fort Lee - Fort Lee Ferry horse car 308 passing the St. Germaine Apartment Building, undated (Box 23, Folder 210)
      - Hoboken - rooftop view of trainyards, undated (Box 23, Folder 210)
      - Long Beach Island Boardwalk, undated (Box 23, Folder 210)
      - Newark - Theodore Roosevelt with statue of Abraham Lincoln in front of Essex County Courthouse, 1911 (Box 23, Folder 210)
      - Paterson - Passaic Falls (4), undated (Box 23, Folder 210)
    - New York
      - Mineola - Old Nassau County Court House, [1900] (Box 23, Folder 211)
      - Ossining - Croton Aquaduct and Dam (7), undated (Box 23, Folder 211)
      - Ossining - Sing Sing Prison, undated (Box 23, Folder 211)
      - Pelhamville - view of forest and brook, undated (Box 23, Folder 211)
      - West Bay Shore [Long Island] - Locust Valley Road, [1902] (Box 23, Folder 212)
      - West Bay Shore [Long Island] - Sagtikos Manor, interiors (18), [1902], undated (Box 23, Folder 212-213)
      - West Bay Shore [Long Island] - Sagtikos Manor, exteriors (3), [1902] (Box 23, Folder 214)
      - Unidentified Long Island views (4), undated (Box 23, Folder 215)
    - Virginia
      - Newport News - oxcart with two women and a laborer, undated (Box 23, Folder 215)
  - Mounted
    - Connecticut
      - New Britain, undated (Box 23, Folder 216)
    - Missouri
      - St. Louis - City Hall, [1905] (Box 24, Folder 217)
      - St. Louis - Eads Bridge, undated (Box 24, Folder 217)
      - St. Louis - Levee (2), undated (Box 24, Folder 217)
      - St. Louis - Louisiana Purchase Exposition buildings under construction, [1903-1904] (Box 24, Folder 218)
      - St. Louis - Planters Hotel, [1905] (Box 24, Folder 218)
      - St. Louis - University of St. Louis, [1905] (Box 24, Folder 218)
    - New Jersey
      - Atlantic City (2), undated (Box 24, Folder 219)
    - New York
      - Albany - Capitol Building, Court of Appeals, interior, undated (Box 24, Folder 220)
      - Albany - Capitol Building, Court room, interior, undated (Box 24, Folder 220)
      - Albany - Capitol Building, Exterior, undated (Box 24, Folder 220)
      - Albany - Capitol Building, Governor's Office, interior (2), [1905] (Box 24, Folder 221)
      - Albany - Capitol Building, Interior, undated (Box 24, Folder 221)
      - Albany - Capitol Building, Lobby corridor, interior, undated (Box 24, Folder 221)
      - Garden City - Cathedral of the Incarnation, interiors and entrance (4), undated (Box 24, Folder 222)
      - Garden City - General view, taken from St. Paul's School, [1900-1914] (Box 24, Folder 223)
      - Garden City - Garden City Fire Department, group in parade, [1900-1914] (Box 24, Folder 223)
      - Garden City - Garden City Golf Links, undated (Box 24, Folder 223)
      - Garden City - St. Mary's School, undated (Box 24, Folder 223)
      - Glen Cove - Union School (2 copies), undated (Box 24, Folder 224)
      - Montauk - ocean views (2), [1905], undated (Box 24, Folder 225)
      - Newburgh, [1905] (Box 25, Folder 226)
      - Niagara Falls (19), undated (Box 25, Folder 227-230)
      - Southhampton - Windmill, undated (Box 25, Folder 231)
      - West Bay Shore - Sagtikos Manor, interiors (10), [1902], undated (Box 25, Folder 232-234)
- Series IV: Photographs by Subject
  Series IV consists of approximately 130 photographs dating from ca. 1886-1914 which are organized into the following subseries: Portraits, Ships, Miscellaneous and Unidentified. Thereunder, they are arranged alphabetically by subject. Portraits include a variety of individuals, including both George P. Hall and James S. Hall and some of their family members. Other photographs in this subseries are mostly of organized groups or clubs, such as the St. Paul's School Mandolin Club, the Hope Fishing Club, and the Tansley Republican Club. Several portraits of unidentified individuals are included.
  The Ships subseries is extensive, and consists mostly of photographs taken in the late 1890s of the U.S. Navy's new steel battleships around the time of the Spanish-American War. Many of the photographs were taken in New York Harbor, but harbor details are usually not included.
  - Portraits - Unmounted
    - Barnard, Frederick A.P., President of Columbia College (1865-1889) [photograph of painting], undated (Box 26, Folder 235)
    - Burns, J.B.G., family portrait on steps of residence, undated (Box 26, Folder 235)
    - Civic Federation, interior, undated (Box 26, Folder 235)
    - Drisler, Henry, Acting President of Columbia College (1888-1890) [photograph of painting], undated (Box 26, Folder 235)